<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sander Schutten's Blog</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Sander Schutten's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 10:48:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sschutten.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Search Results</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/search/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/search/</guid><description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml ``` [outputs] home = [&amp;ldquo;HTML&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;JSON&amp;rdquo;] ```</description></item><item><title>Difference between Apply to each and For each actions</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2019/10/difference-between-apply-to-each-and-for-each-actions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 10:48:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2019/10/difference-between-apply-to-each-and-for-each-actions/</guid><description>Microsoft Flow and Azure Logic Apps are based on the same platform and therefor very similar. There are, however, cases where they&amp;rsquo;re a little different. Take for example the Apply to each (Flow) action and the For each (Logic Apps) action. They&amp;rsquo;re very similar in that they execute the actions for each of the items in the array. There&amp;rsquo;s one caveat though and that is the default concurrency setting.
Apply to each action</description></item><item><title>Intelligent chatbots for Microsoft Teams</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2019/09/intelligent-digital-assitants/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 07:10:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2019/09/intelligent-digital-assitants/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re living in the decade of the rise of conversational platforms like chatbots. Gartner predicts that by 2022 over 70% of modern workers use conversational platforms on a daily basis. Chatbots are around for many years, even dating back to 1966, with fluctuating interest over time. The last few years we see a big increase of excitement for chatbots with artificial intelligence (AI) becoming mainstream. The use of AI enables chatbots to better understand natural language and be able to more intelligently respond to users.</description></item><item><title>Custom profile images in Edge</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2019/08/edge-multi-profile-with-custom-images/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 06:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2019/08/edge-multi-profile-with-custom-images/</guid><description>Ever since Microsoft announced the next version of Edge will be based on Chromium and provided the Edge Insider program I&amp;rsquo;ve been happily running the Dev channel of Edge. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t tried yet, you should. It&amp;rsquo;s that good.
One of the benefits of the Chromium based Edge is that it brings profiles to Edge. Profiles are great, because they allow you to have separate profiles for different purposes, e.g. a work profile and a personal profile.</description></item><item><title>Connect to Azure AD secured SignalR Hub from your SPFx code</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2018/12/connect-azure-ad-authenticated-signalr-hub-from-spfx/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2018/12/connect-azure-ad-authenticated-signalr-hub-from-spfx/</guid><description>SignalR is a great technology to provide users with real-time UI updates of events happening in the back-end. It&amp;rsquo;s a perfect match with SPFX to build some amazing web parts for SharePoint. With the recent release of ASPNET SignalR Core (now incorporated in the ASP.NET Core GitHub project) SignalR is easier to use than before. So you&amp;rsquo;ve gone and created a web part that connects to a SignalR hub and the experience makes a real impact for your users.</description></item><item><title>Logic Apps improvement suggestions</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2018/02/logic-apps-improvement-suggestions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2018/02/logic-apps-improvement-suggestions/</guid><description>I must say that Logic Apps has come a long way in its brief lifetime. It&amp;rsquo;s surprisingly easy to get up and go with Logic Apps and the number of available connectors is crazy. However there are still a couple of things that could be improved to make it friendlier for the more serious applications. Here&amp;rsquo;s my list.
The last few weeks I had the chance to spend a lot of time with Azure Logic Apps.</description></item><item><title>Move your development VM to Azure</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2013/06/move-your-development-vm-to-azure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 07:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2013/06/move-your-development-vm-to-azure/</guid><description>During my day job I regularly had to use virtual machines to do my work on. It just simply isn&amp;rsquo;t convenient to run BizTalk Server or SharePoint on you laptop. I&amp;rsquo;ve used many types and brands of virtualisation software like Virtual PC, Virtual Server and VMWare. More recently I started using Hyper-V, which, because baked into Windows 8, sounds like a very natural thing to do.
Unfortunately, whatever software I used, the performance I get just doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide a good user experience.</description></item><item><title>Preparing for 70-485: Advanced Metro style App Development using C#</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2012/09/preparing-for-70-485-advanced-metro-style-app-development-using-c/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 10:05:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2012/09/preparing-for-70-485-advanced-metro-style-app-development-using-c/</guid><description>A few weeks agoI posted learning material for preparing for exam 70-484. In the meanwhile I also took the 70-485: Advanced Metro style App Development using C# exam and used the information below for my preparation. As the exam was still in beta I don’t know yet whether I passed the exam, but I doubt it. You really need to make sure you’ve got hands-on experience with each of the topics.</description></item><item><title>Preparing for 70-484: Essentials of Developing Windows Metro style Apps using C#</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2012/09/preparing-for-70-484-essentials-of-developing-windows-metro-style-apps-using-c/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 14:01:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2012/09/preparing-for-70-484-essentials-of-developing-windows-metro-style-apps-using-c/</guid><description>Last week I took the 70-484: Essentials of Developing Windows Metro style Apps using C# exam. In preparation for the exam I used the resources below. Hopefully they can help you too preparing for the exam.
Design Metro style Apps (19%) Design the UI layout and structure. http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms750613.aspx http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.windows.style.aspx Design for separation of concerns (SOC). http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechDays/TechDays-2012-Belgium/282 Apply the MVVM pattern to your app design. http://dotnetspeak.com/index.php/2012/07/working-with-gridview-control-in-winrt-app/ http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windows/apps/BR209833 Design and implement Process Lifetime Management (PLM).</description></item><item><title>Lightswitch: custom ribbon button</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/08/lightswitch-custom-ribbon-button/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 18:10:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/08/lightswitch-custom-ribbon-button/</guid><description>Two weeks ago, on July 26th, Visual Studio Lightswitch 2011 was released. I ‘d seen a couple of videos what you can do with Lightswitch so I though I’d put it to the test by developing a replacement for a tool I use at one of my clients. Lightswitch is really easy to use and I believe I can actually teach my wife to create data-centric application using it. Until you reach the limits though, because than it becomes more difficult really fast.</description></item><item><title>Windows Phone 7 Mango features</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/07/windows-phone-7-mango-features/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 11:40:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/07/windows-phone-7-mango-features/</guid><description>A lot has been said and written about Windows Phone 7 Mango. The eagerly awaited update to Microsoft’s new Windows Phone platform is said to sport 500 new features, bringing it up to par with its competition. While 500 features sound a lot, it may well be achieved if you count every little detail. Many of the bigger features can be found all over the web, especially in the much detailed Engadget in-depth preview.</description></item><item><title>MIX11: Day 3</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-day-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 11:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-day-3/</guid><description>It’s a wrap, MIX11 is over. Yesterday was the last day of MIX and many people have already returned to their homes. There was not much news to be shared, but here are my findings anyway.
Designer and Developer: A Case for the Hybrid (Jeff Croft) In this talk Jeff Croft talks about what makes good designers and developers. His statement is that designers should know how to program and developers should know how to design.</description></item><item><title>MIX11: Day 2</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-day-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 11:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-day-2/</guid><description>Today was a really interesting day, with lots of new stuff being announced and sessions packed with interesting information. These are my findings of this day.
Keynote (Joe Belfiore, Scott Guthrie) The keynote started off with an inspiring viral video. It appears a fan of Windows Phone created it by request of Microsoft after he created his own viral out of love of the phone. If the viral gets over 200k of views on YouTube, it is turned into a real commercial.</description></item><item><title>MIX11: Day 1</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-day-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 11:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-day-1/</guid><description>Today was the first conference day and my second day at MIX11. The day began with a keynote and after that a couple of sessions. These are my findings of today.
Keynote (Dean Hachamovitch, Scott Guthrie) Dean started off with looking back at the development of IE9 and how successful is has been so far. Then he announced that they’re already three weeks into development of IE10, which didn’t come as a surprise looking at the shirt he was wearing with a bit TEN on it with the ‘E’ being the IE logo.</description></item><item><title>MIX11: Boot Camps</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-boot-camps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 11:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-boot-camps/</guid><description>Today was the preconference day at MIX11, which means boot camps for everyone that applied for them. There were options for the morning and afternoon boot camps and I chose the Silverlight and SharePoint &amp;amp; Silverlight boot camps. This is a brief summary of what I think were things of interest.
Silverlight boot camp I didn’t came to this boot camp to improve my knowledge on Silverlight, but more because of the speakers: John Papa and Mike Taulty.</description></item><item><title>Advanced MVVM: Doing visual states properly</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/03/advanced-mvvm-doing-visual-states-properly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2011 12:17:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/03/advanced-mvvm-doing-visual-states-properly/</guid><description>An important plus of rich internet applications is the potential user experience you can achieve by applying UX patterns. A part of this is the visual states and their transitions. A visual state determines what the user interface looks like at a certain point in time and the transitions describe how the application moves from one visual state to the other, many times using animations to enhance the experience.</description></item><item><title>Using the Sync Framework on Windows Phone 7</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/01/using-the-sync-framework-on-windows-phone-7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 13:18:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/01/using-the-sync-framework-on-windows-phone-7/</guid><description>For a mobile platform, like Windows Phone 7, you may be required to allow an application to work even when there’s no data connection available. Doing so is not that easy. You need to manage state locally, synchronize changed data (one-way or duplex) and maybe even handle conflicts. Luckily Microsoft offers the Sync Framework which makes it easier for you to accomplish this by taking much of the required plumbing out of your hands completely.</description></item><item><title>Building a location aware Windows Phone 7 application</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2010/12/building-a-location-aware-windows-phone-7-application-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 15:41:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2010/12/building-a-location-aware-windows-phone-7-application-2/</guid><description>The Windows Phone 7 SDK contains a couple of APIs for interacting with different parts of the phone hardware, like accessing the camera or initiating a phone call. One of the cool APIs of Windows Phone 7 is the Location API. Just as in the desktop version of .NET Framework 4.0, the Location API enables you to get the approximate location of the user. To find the location of the user, the API uses GPS, WiFi or cell tower triangulation, where the first is the most and the latter least accurate.</description></item><item><title>WCF RIA Services OData endpoint does NOT support update or LINQ</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2010/11/wcf-ria-services-odata-endpoint-does-not-support-update-or-linq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 17:46:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2010/11/wcf-ria-services-odata-endpoint-does-not-support-update-or-linq/</guid><description>After struggling with WCF RIA Services v1 (Silverlight 4 RTM) to enable insert/update for the OData endpoint for use with Windows Phone 7, I finally figured it out. The current version of WCF RIA Services does NOT support update or LINQ! I think I searched for a couple of hours until I found the single line of information on this in this following Silverlight TV post:
NOTE: The ODATA endpoint has very limited support in V1.</description></item><item><title>MCE Guide Editor source code</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2009/01/mce-guide-editor-source-code/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 07:21:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2009/01/mce-guide-editor-source-code/</guid><description>I got a few requests for the source code of MCE Guide Editor. I once started working on a new release of it and during the process I discovered that the solution I chose wasn’t going to work. This meant I didn’t have the source of the working version of the tool. What I did was disassemble the executable. I’m currently working on a Windows 7 PC, so I wasn’t able to compile the disassembled code because I’m missing the ehome dll.</description></item><item><title>Honk twice if you see us!</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/11/honk-twice-if-you-see-us/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2008 10:15:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/11/honk-twice-if-you-see-us/</guid><description>Today I witnessed the arrival of eight Avanade branded Fiat 500 cars. They arrived in a single line in front of our main office, where they stand now. The orange / black color combination draws a lot of attention and enthousiasm. Together with the branding and racing stripes they form the perfect car for our core services team. Secretly, in our hearts, the customer facing employees, driving our big luxurous lease cars, would die to drive one of these babies ourselves.</description></item><item><title>Building Vista Media Center Add-ins (Dutch)</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/11/building-vista-media-center-add-ins-dutch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2008 15:05:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/11/building-vista-media-center-add-ins-dutch/</guid><description>It’s been a while since I wrote an article on developing Vista Media Center Add-ins. A month ago the article was published in the Dutch .Net Magazine and today I found the digital version is available as well. In the article I demonstrate how to use the Viddler.com API to get a list of videos and display them in your add-in. The goal was to build a player for Viddler.com videos, but unfortunately the API method for getting the raw video is still not available.</description></item><item><title>Day 0: arrived in LA</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/day-0-arrived-in-la/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 13:20:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/day-0-arrived-in-la/</guid><description>Yesterday afternoon we (my collegues and I) arrived in LA. Purpose of visit: the Microsoft Professional Developer Conference 2008 (PDC’08). It promises to be a very interesting week with a lot of new stuff from Microsoft, including Windows 7, ‘Oslo’ and ‘Dublin’. After arrival we checked into our rooms, grabbed a slice of pizza, had a drink and went to bed. We tried to join the party by Jeffrey Pallermo, but the waiting time was about 40 minutes and we heard there was no more beer (no problem for me as non-alcohol drinking person, but some of my collegues seemed to mind :)).</description></item><item><title>Consume WCF service using Sharepoint Designer</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/consume-wcf-service-using-sharepoint-designer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 08:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/consume-wcf-service-using-sharepoint-designer/</guid><description>By default the SharePoint Designer is unable to consume WCF services because it fails to recognize the structure of the request messages. There is a workaround if you still need to consume WCF services using the Designer. However, this does not work via the datasource wizard but instead requires some manual intervention. There are two methods to do accomplish this:
Modify the datasource Modify the code in the page The first method is easier to implement and gives you more control over the output.</description></item><item><title>Better WSSF solution structure</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/better-wssf-solution-structure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 07:53:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/better-wssf-solution-structure/</guid><description>I’ve done my share of work with the Web Service Software Factory modelling edition, but never have I liked the solution structure it generates for me. Or either the namespaces of the projects are wrong, or the paths became too long because of the fully qualified names I’d use. This time I reserved some time to tackle this once and for all. The result is an easy to apply patch for WSSF: Modelling Edition.</description></item><item><title>Viddler.Net on Codeplex</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/08/viddlernet-on-codeplex/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2008 16:23:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/08/viddlernet-on-codeplex/</guid><description>Things are moving fast. Yesterday I released an early first version of Viddler.Net, a wrapper for the Viddle API. Today I was able to post an updated version to Codeplex, which seems more suitable for managing this project than my own blog. The updated version uses HTTP POST instead of GET and includes one extra implemented method to upload videos.
Find the Codeplex project at http://www.codeplex.com/ViddlerDotNet</description></item><item><title>First release of Viddler.Net</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/08/first-release-of-viddlernet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 18:13:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/08/first-release-of-viddlernet/</guid><description>If you read my article in the Dutch .Net Magazine about Vista Media Center add-ins and you came looking on my blog for the Viddler.Net api, you just found it! If you don’t know what I’m talking about, please read on This is my first release of the Viddler.Net api, which is a wrapper for the Viddler api. The Viddler.Net api allows a .Net developer to make use of the videos on the Viddler website through code.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft BizTalk Server Performance Optimization Guide</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/microsoft-biztalk-server-performance-optimization-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2008 07:43:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/microsoft-biztalk-server-performance-optimization-guide/</guid><description>From MSDN:
Welcome to the first edition of the Microsoft® BizTalk® Server Performance Optimizations Guide. We created this guide to provide in depth information for optimizing the performance of a BizTalk Server solution. Full end-to-end performance testing is frequently overlooked during enterprise application deployment. Knowing that Microsoft has built a scalable messaging infrastructure, many organizations that use BizTalk Server spend little or no time conducting performance testing of their own applications.</description></item><item><title>Control Windows Media Center with New Windows SideShow BETA Gadgets</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/control-windows-media-center-with-new-windows-sideshow-beta-gadgets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2008 10:23:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/control-windows-media-center-with-new-windows-sideshow-beta-gadgets/</guid><description>From the Windows Experience Blog:
The Windows SideShow Team has announced the availability of 4 BETA Windows SideShow Gadgets that let you control Windows Media Center from a Windows Sideshow device. You can sign-up via Microsoft Connect to gain access to Beta Test these new Windows SideShow Gadgets:
http://connect.microsoft.com/InvitationUse.aspx?ProgramID=2380&amp;amp;SiteID=312&amp;amp;InvitationID=GPB-79MM-RFJ2
Here is the breakdown of the 4 Windows Media Center BETA Windows SideShow Gadgets and what they do:
Now Playing: View what is currently playing in Windows Media Center (includes playback controls) Pictures + Video: Browse your Photos and Videos folders Music: Browse your Music folder and play any song TV: Look at what is on TV via the Windows Media Center Guide, Schedule Recordings, and View Recordings (in a Thumbnail view)</description></item><item><title>BizUnit Designer</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/bizunit-designer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2008 05:21:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/bizunit-designer/</guid><description>From CodePlex:
BizUnit Designer is a GUI that allows rapid creation of BizUnit test cases which can be used for unit testing or system testing distributed applications. The easy to use drag and drop user interface has minimal learning curve which will get you up and running with test cases in a matter of minutes.
I’ve used BizUnit on a couple of projects (even non-BizTalk projects) and I think it’s very useful.</description></item><item><title>More BizTalk posters</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/more-biztalk-posters/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2008 12:42:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/more-biztalk-posters/</guid><description>Somebody at the product team has really started a rush to push out these nice looking posters. Here is a rather new one:
BizTalk Server 2006 R2 Database Infrastructure Poster
http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=24662FB5-622C-4E7E-9E83-505D1F664C4D&amp;amp;displaylang=en
And as a service to those of you that haven’t seen anyone of these:
BizTalk Server 2006 R2 Runtime Architecture Poster
http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=8790E652-1DA5-4E80-88FE-B87606233DB4&amp;amp;displaylang=en
BizTalk Server 2006 R2 Capabilities Poster
http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=34F41573-C552-466F-B531-32CB09A57CDD&amp;amp;displaylang=en
BizTalk Server 2006 R2 Scale-Out Configurations Poster
http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=FF468298-64BE-4947-A086-F61584CAF995&amp;amp;displaylang=en</description></item><item><title>Home Server campaign</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/86/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2008 12:07:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/86/</guid><description>[](File URL) in case you haven’t seen this yet, Microsoft has a rather interesting marketing campaign around Windows Home Server. One of the parts of the campaign is a book about Home Server which looks like it’s written for kids. The book explains what the magic &amp;lsquo;Server&amp;rsquo; in the house is all about.
Microsoft went so far with this campaign that it actually looks like you can buy the book from Amazon!</description></item><item><title>How-To: New ASP.NET 3.5 Extensions Video Screencasts</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/84/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2008 11:40:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/84/</guid><description>From the almighty Scott Hanselman:
Released today are four new screencasts about the ASP.NET 3.5 Extensions by various members of the ASP.NET team. Every video is available in numerous formats, and note that this also includes re-encoded versions of my **Intro to MVC Screencast **in a pile of formats including an iPod/iTouch compatible format, as well as ones for the **Zune **and **PSP **and a utterly unwatchable 😉 40 meg 3GP one for 3G Phones.</description></item><item><title>Video: BizTalk Services Explained</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/video-biztalk-services-explained/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2008 11:32:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/video-biztalk-services-explained/</guid><description>In this video, James Conard talks with John Shewchuk and Dennis Pilarinos about BizTalk Services.
In the simplest definition, BizTalk Services simplifies application connectivity by extending WCF and providing a set of hosted services. John and Dennis quickly explain BizTalk Services by discussing the challenges with building applications today. Dennis also shows four demos of BizTalk Services and then drops into Visual Studio along the way to show the programming model.</description></item><item><title>Released: BizTalk Server 2006 extentions for WF</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/released-biztalk-server-2006-extentions-for-wf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2008 11:26:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/released-biztalk-server-2006-extentions-for-wf/</guid><description>Just released (oh well, a couple of months ago), the long awaited BizTalk Server 2006 extensions for Windows Workflow Foundation SDK. Use WF modeling and host workflows in BizTalk Server. Note the BTS messaging activities in the image.
The new BizTalk Server edition will most likely sport the Workflow Designer instead of the plain old Orchestration Designer. This probably results into something that looks a lot like what you get with the extentions.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft LoadGen 2007</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/microsoft-loadgen-2007/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2008 11:03:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/microsoft-loadgen-2007/</guid><description>Microsoft LoadGen 2007 generates message transmission loads to run performance and stress tests for your Microsoft BizTalk Server applications, and provides performance counters to monitor the performance of the infrastructure running BizTalk Server.
This tool is intended for developers and IT professionals to simulate load on a BizTalk Server. Using this tool, you can simulate load to instrument performance and stress against a BizTalk deployment. In addition, this tool may also be extended by developers to simulate load for custom transports.</description></item><item><title>BizTalk Server capabilities poster</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/biztalk-server-capabilities-poster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2008 10:24:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/biztalk-server-capabilities-poster/</guid><description>From the source:
This poster lists the BizTalk Server 2006 R2 capabilities bucketed in categories and is designed to provide both a high level and a detailed view of the capabilities and features that are included in the product. (When printed in full scale this poster size is: 35x 32)
Download the poster here.</description></item><item><title>FarPoint Spread for BizTalk Server 2006</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/farpoint-spread-for-biztalk-server-2006/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2008 08:41:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/farpoint-spread-for-biztalk-server-2006/</guid><description>If you’ve ever wanted or needed to parse Excel files using BizTalk, you can now. Some time ago FarPoint released a pipeline dissassembler component for BizTalk Server 2006 which is able to convert Excel files into XML. From their website:
Spread for BizTalk Server 2006 provides a complete solution for integrating Microsoft Excel data seamlessly into your BizTalk applications.
Spread includes a pipeline disassembler that parses Excel data (XLS, Excel 2007 XML, CSV, TXT) into XML, and a pipeline assembler that creates Excel (XLS, Excel 2007 XML) and PDF documents from XML data in BizTalk Applications.</description></item><item><title>Map xs:string to xs:datetime</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/map-xsstring-to-xsdatetime/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 13:33:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/map-xsstring-to-xsdatetime/</guid><description>Remember that situation where you needed to convert a string representation of a DateTime to a valid DataTime using the BizTalk mapper? No? Well, I do. The parsing of the string as a DateTime is not the real problem here. Once you know how the string is formatted it is simply writing a way to parse it, either using substrings or using the DateTime.Parse method. Once you have a DateTime though, you need to format it to be valid according to the XSD spec.</description></item><item><title>First look at WCF Adapter for BizTalk Server 2006 R2</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/first-look-at-wcf-adapter-for-biztalk-server-2006-r2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 13:17:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/first-look-at-wcf-adapter-for-biztalk-server-2006-r2/</guid><description>Although the WCF adapter for BizTalk Server 2006 R2 has been released a while ago, I found that a coworker of mine had created a simple and short video explaining all the basics of using the WCF adapter. If you haven’t used the adapter before or just want to see how easy it is to use the adapter, go see the video here.</description></item><item><title>Ext JS</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/ext-js/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 13:04:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/07/ext-js/</guid><description>Although I rarely develop front-end applications, let alone web applications, during my day-to-day job, I’m still practicing the skill in my personal time. Before my interests in application integration started to arise I was very much intrigued by all what is currently known as web 2.0 and Ajax. In the time we would simply call it DHTML, but that term was superseded by the more catchy ones.
So if I see someting passing by that really looks cool and is built using simply Javascript and HTML I always take a quick look at it.</description></item><item><title>BizTalk Server 2006 R3 just around the corner</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/04/biztalk-server-2006-r3-just-around-the-corner/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 09:34:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/04/biztalk-server-2006-r3-just-around-the-corner/</guid><description>Quote: “Once SQL Server 2008 (…) becomes generally available, we will follow with an updated version of BizTalk Server designed for the latest versions of Windows Server, the .NET Framework, Visual Studio, and SQL Server. This will mean that BizTalk Server customers will continue to take full advantage of the platform’s latest improvements including: scalability for mission-critical workloads, improved support for next-generation web and service oriented applications, improved virtualization support and better business insight through Office.</description></item><item><title>Status update on MCE Guide Editor</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/03/status-update-on-mce-guide-editor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 17:47:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/03/status-update-on-mce-guide-editor/</guid><description>A lot of people are waiting for a new release of MCE Guide Editor which hopefully fixes the bug that the channel order gets mixed up again after a reboot. Somewhere in the comments of the old post I mentioned I thought I’d found the bug and it was just a matter of days until the fix could be released. I was testing the tool agains a simulated set-up with preconfigured UPC guide listings.</description></item><item><title>Jonas Butt, the new IT-talent?</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/02/jonas-butt-the-new-it-talent/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2008 09:21:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/02/jonas-butt-the-new-it-talent/</guid><description>IT-talent is an internship project which offers IT-talents an exclusive assignment with a prominent IT company. The goal is to create an unique experience and a solid basis for a successful career in IT. Check out www.it-talenten.nl (Dutch) for more information on this project.
One of the eight participating students is Jonas Butt, who’s doing his internship at Avanade Netherlands. During his internship he’ll try to answer the following research question:</description></item><item><title>Running</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/02/63/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 15:44:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/02/63/</guid><description>For about 5 months now I’m running with a couple of friends. We started out with a small route in the woods, but that got a little too dark in the winter. One time I was running right behind one of my fellow runners and I couln’t see anything but his white shoes. Suddenly I noticed the path was way to our right and we were standing somewhere in the middle of some schrubs.</description></item><item><title>DevDays 2007, were you there?</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/06/devdays-2007-were-you-there/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 18:37:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/06/devdays-2007-were-you-there/</guid><description>DevDays 2007…I was there, but were you? For those of you living in the Netherlands, Microsoft held the 2007 edition of DevDays and off course Avanade was well represented. On the main plaza you could find our stand where we were running an XNA demo on two giant plasma screens. One was running on a laptop and the other live on a Xbox360. Okay, Avanade doesn’t actually do projects using XNA, but we didn’t mind.</description></item><item><title>First release of MCE Guide Editor</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/05/first-release-of-mce-guide-editor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 18:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/05/first-release-of-mce-guide-editor/</guid><description>Today I released the first edition of MCE Guide Editor. I created this tool because of the very long list of channels I got since I use satellite tv. Reordering the channels is a real pain in the ass if you use the Media Center user interface. Here’s where MCE Guide Editor comes in…
MCE Guide Editor allows you to change the order of channels of your Media Center setup in an easy way, using drag and drop.</description></item><item><title>.Net Magazine article published online</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/02/net-magazine-article-published-online/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2007 07:53:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/02/net-magazine-article-published-online/</guid><description>Today I found out that my article on BAM for the Dutch .Net Magazine of december 2006 is published online. It’s an introduction to BAM and I wrote it because I think BAM is far underused at the moment.
If you understand Dutch you might want to check it out here.
Ex-collegue Dick Dijkstra also wrote an article for the same edition of the .Net Magazine. His article is about the new and improved error handling methods in BizTalk Server 2006.</description></item><item><title>MCTS BizTalk Server 2006</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/mcts-biztalk-server-2006/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2007 11:22:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/mcts-biztalk-server-2006/</guid><description>Today I passed the 70-235 exam, required for earning the MCTS BizTalk Server 2006 certification. About 20% of the questions was related to the Business Rule Engine (BRE) and another 15% to Business Activity Monitoring (BAM). The other questions were all general BizTalk questions, including some questions on Role Links. I found the exam a little difficult, mainly because I haven’t worked with the BRE that much and also haven’t used Role Links.</description></item><item><title>Playing Blog-Tag</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/playing-blog-tag/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 14:41:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/playing-blog-tag/</guid><description>Jolly, they got me! Dennis just tagged me. At first I had no clue what it meant, but it seems a game of tag, and now I’m it. This means I have to write five things not much people know about me. So here it goes My girlfriend is Tamara Bos and we’re together for over 7.5 years now. She’s my first and only true love and we are very happy with each other, especially now we are living together in Almere since last october.</description></item><item><title>BizTalk shell extension</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/biztalk-shell-extension/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 16:02:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/biztalk-shell-extension/</guid><description>I would like to share one interesting tool I came across. This is a tool for Viewing BizTalk Assemblies Deployed on BizTalk Server. Not only you can view the deployed assemblies but can also view the contents of the assembly by double clicking on assembly. Also you can dive deeper by double clicking the individual BizTalk Artifact where you can view more detailed info. Say if, you double click a schema of an assembly you will see the schema of that particular message.</description></item><item><title>BizTalk Troubleshooting Guide</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/biztalk-troubleshooting-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 15:53:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/biztalk-troubleshooting-guide/</guid><description>For beginners BizTalk can be really difficult to learn. They don’t know how to perform certain tasks and are stunned by a lot of (for them) cryptical warnings and errors. Luckily there’s the BizTalk Troubleshooting Guide which covers most (if not all) of the tasks, messages, tips, trics, know-hows and what else. Even for an experienced BizTalk enthousiast like me it contains a lot of interesting stuff. Use it as your BizTalk bible.</description></item><item><title>Accessing flat file content in orchestration</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/accessing-flat-file-content-in-orchestration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/accessing-flat-file-content-in-orchestration/</guid><description>Sometimes the requirement for your BizTalk solution is to receive a flat file (read: not xml) in your orchestration an do something with the data. An example could be receiving a PDF file and extracting some portions of data out of it. Some BizTalk developers already know that you can receive whatever file without treating it as XML by using System.Xml.XmlDocument as its message type (sounds silly doesn’t it?). After you’ve received the message you can’t access it as you normally do because it’s still a byte stream.</description></item><item><title>Storing configuration inside SSO database</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/storing-configuration-inside-sso-database/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 15:16:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/storing-configuration-inside-sso-database/</guid><description>Maybe the simplest way to store configuration data for your BizTalk solution is to use the BTSNTSvc.exe.config file and the System.Configuration namespace to access that data. Most of the time I’m using this method on projects, but it introduces problems in BizTalk farms because you need to keep the configuration in sync. Another way would be to use a database, but that still requires a connection string to be present somewhere (again the BTSNTSvc.</description></item><item><title>BizTalk Adapter whitepaper</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/biztalk-adapter-whitepaper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 14:51:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/biztalk-adapter-whitepaper/</guid><description>Mike McKeown has a great blog where he elaborates on BizTalk Adapter development. He has some nice tutorials, howto’s and whitepapers listed on his blog. Some time ago he released a BizTalk Adapter developent whitepaper regarding transactional adapters and adapter base classes. You should definetely read this if you’re involved in developing new adapters. Also don’t forget to read his other material.</description></item><item><title>Pipeline Testing Framework for BTS06</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/pipeline-testing-framework-for-bts06/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 14:44:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/pipeline-testing-framework-for-bts06/</guid><description>Tomas Restrepo wrote a really useful framework to test pipelines and pipeline components. Some time ago he released the first version of his framework and posted a couple of howto’s to get you started. It’s definitely worth stopping by his blog.</description></item><item><title>Using BAM API to create related activities</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/using-bam-api-to-create-related-activities/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 14:37:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2007/01/using-bam-api-to-create-related-activities/</guid><description>Check out this great post by Richard Seroter on using the BAM API to collect BAM data inside a loop, creating a hierarchy of activities. Not doing too much with the BAM API I found it a great way to understand it’s usage and flexibility.</description></item><item><title>Add existing project from web drama</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/11/add-existing-project-from-web-drama/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2006 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/11/add-existing-project-from-web-drama/</guid><description>Are you tired of dealing with the drama regarding adding an existing project from web in Visual Studio? If so read on, because if you follow these steps tightly you’re ready to go in a minute, or … well, faster then figuring this one out yourself Open your solution in Visual Studio and choose Add &amp;gt; Existing Project From Web Type the url to your site, e.g. http://localhost/YourSite This is the important part: in the open file dialog, instead of browsing to the project file, type the full url to your project file, e.</description></item><item><title>Developing for Vista Media Center</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/03/developing-for-vista-media-center/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2006 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/03/developing-for-vista-media-center/</guid><description>Aaah! I’ve read some very good news today. For some time now, I’m looking into developing plug-ins for XP Media Center, but I dislike the way it works. It looks like with Vista all my dreams will come true!
For XP one could develop plug-ins in the form of simple HTML pages, so it would always look as if the plug-in was bolted onto the side. Vista, in return, makes use of the eXtensible Markup Language defined with Windows Presentation Foundation.</description></item><item><title>HTML Generator Stylesheet for BizTalk 2004 Maps</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/03/html-generator-stylesheet-for-biztalk-2004-maps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2006 12:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/03/html-generator-stylesheet-for-biztalk-2004-maps/</guid><description>Almost every BizTalk artifact is beautifully documentable, especially using the BizTalk Documenter. One thing that’s always hard to document are the maps. Finally someone came up with a solution and that someone is Steve Hart.
The HTML Generator Stylesheet for BizTalk 2004 Maps is an XSLT which transforms the data of a map into viewable HTML. Although the approach is a good one, I’m not really sure about the added value.</description></item><item><title>Increase XSLT performance by using xls:key</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/03/increase-xslt-performance-by-using-xlskey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2006 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/03/increase-xslt-performance-by-using-xlskey/</guid><description>hlight: white; mso-ansi-language: EN-US”&amp;gt;&amp;lt;SPAN style=”mso-spacerun: yes”&amp;gt; /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;SPAN style=”FONT-SIZE: 8pt; BACKGROUND: white; COLOR: black; FONT-FAMILY: ‘Courier New'; mso-bidi-font-size: 12.0pt; mso-highlight: white; mso-ansi-language: EN-US”&amp;gt; &amp;lt;o:p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/o:p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;P class=MsoNormal style=”MARGIN: 0in 0in 0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none”&amp;gt;&amp;lt;SPAN style=”FONT-SIZE: 8pt; BACKGROUND: white; COLOR: black; FONT-FAMILY: ‘Courier New'; mso-bidi-font-size: 12.0pt; mso-highlight: white; mso-ansi-language: EN-US”&amp;gt;&amp;lt;SPAN style=”mso-tab-count: 1″&amp;gt; &amp;lt;o:p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/o:p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;P class=MsoNormal style=”MARGIN: 0in 0in 0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none”&amp;gt;&amp;lt;SPAN style=”FONT-SIZE: 8pt; BACKGROUND: white; COLOR: black; FONT-FAMILY: ‘Courier New'; mso-bidi-font-size: 12.0pt; mso-highlight: white; mso-ansi-language: EN-US”&amp;gt;&amp;lt;SPAN style=”mso-spacerun: yes”&amp;gt; &amp;lt;SPAN style=”FONT-SIZE: 8pt; BACKGROUND: white; COLOR: blue; FONT-FAMILY: ‘Courier New'; mso-bidi-font-size: 12.</description></item><item><title>DevDays 7 &amp;amp; 8 March</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/devdays-7-8-march/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2006 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/devdays-7-8-march/</guid><description>This March the DevDays are coming to Amsterdam and I will be there to speak on BizTalk Server 2006 together with collegae Matt Joe, who is flown in from Seattle. I will be doing some demos involving BAM and in-order processing.
Matt will also be accompanying Dennis Mulder in a very promising talk on Windows Workflow Foundation.
Last but not least my manager Edwin Jongsma will enlighten everyone on the subject of Software Factories (Domain Specific Languages).</description></item><item><title>BizTalk Load Generation Utility reloaded</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/biztalk-load-generation-utility-reloaded/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/biztalk-load-generation-utility-reloaded/</guid><description>The BizTalk load generation utility, originally released by Microsoft several months ago, was quickly removed from their downloads page for enhancement. The enhanced version is now available for download here.
The interesting part is that this tool works with the Performance Tester Tool of Larry Beck (see post below).</description></item><item><title>BizTalk Performance Tester released</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/biztalk-performance-tester-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 07:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/biztalk-performance-tester-released/</guid><description>Better late then never, but about a month ago Larry Beck released the completed version of the BizTalk Performance Tester (BTSPerfTester). This application is intended to provide developers with an easily implemented and predictable method of determining the maximum sustainable throughput of their BizTalk solutions.
You can get it from his blog here.</description></item><item><title>Suppress XML documentation warnings for a project</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/01/suppress-xml-documentation-warnings-for-a-project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2006 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/01/suppress-xml-documentation-warnings-for-a-project/</guid><description>When I turned on the feature to output an XML documentation file when building my project I’m confronted with a load of warnings that the XML documentation is missing for some method. While it’s nice to see these warnings I didn’t want to see them anymore without lowering the warning level. So I searched the net and found a way to suppress these warnings:
Go to the properties of your project.</description></item><item><title>Identify node type in XSLT</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/01/identify-node-type-in-xslt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2006 06:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/01/identify-node-type-in-xslt/</guid><description>For a BizTalk solution I needed to write some custom XSLT. In the XSLT I needed to determine the node type and according to the type execute a specific piece of XSLT. Unfortunately it’s not very easy to get the node type in XSLT. It took me a while to find this post which explains a solution for this. Maybe it could help you out.
http://www.stylusstudio.com/xsllist/200312/post00260.html</description></item><item><title>Happy new year!</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/01/happy-new-year/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/01/happy-new-year/</guid><description>From this place I would like to wish both readers of this blog a happy new year. My target for 2006 is to grow this blog and hopefully more people will read it.</description></item><item><title>Load XmlSchema&amp;#039;s from BizTalk assembly</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/12/load-xmlschemas-from-biztalk-assembly/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2005 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/12/load-xmlschemas-from-biztalk-assembly/</guid><description>That BizTalk compiles your XmlSchema’s into an assembly is great, but wouldn’t it be greater if you could reuse those schema’s in your code? No more hassle of different versions of your schema and your schema’s always at your fingertips because they are in the GAC. Well…it took me a while to figure that it’s actually really simple to do.
To load a schema from an external assembly just instantiate the class which describes your schema.</description></item><item><title>BizTalk Server 2006 CTM Released</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/biztalk-server-2006-ctm-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/biztalk-server-2006-ctm-released/</guid><description>As per monday October 7th Microsoft released BizTalk Server 2006 CTM. This release is only available for users with a MSDN or TechNet account. The CTM release of BizTalk Server 2006 is fully compatible with Visual Studio 2005 and SQL Server 2005. I just can smell the RTM version coming very soon.</description></item><item><title>Access message properties inside custom pipeline component</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/access-message-properties-inside-custom-pipeline-component/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 09:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/access-message-properties-inside-custom-pipeline-component/</guid><description>Just recently I was looking for some default message properties and how to read and write them inside a custom pipeline component. While searching I stumbled over a great post listing all the default message properties and how to read them.
If you want to access the properties in your custom pipeline component, you have to get the IBaseMessageContext object from the IBaseContext and use the Read method to get a value or the Write method to substitute a value with your own.</description></item><item><title>BizTalk&amp;#039;s sexy new XSLT mapper</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/biztalks-sexy-new-xslt-mapper/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 08:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/biztalks-sexy-new-xslt-mapper/</guid><description>I’ve just watched a clip from Channel9 featuring Eddie Churchill. In the video he demonstrates a prototype of the future BizTalk mapper. The new mapper will contain some very impressive features as I must say. Some of them make the life of the mapper a lot easier, especially when dealing with large maps.
Some of the features which are shown in the video are:
Different drawing densities for lines which are in view and which aren’t.</description></item><item><title>Workflow designer will substitute orchestration designer in BizTalk vNext</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/10/workflow-designer-will-substitute-orchestration-designer-in-biztalk-vnext/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2005 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/10/workflow-designer-will-substitute-orchestration-designer-in-biztalk-vnext/</guid><description>I heard it from collegues who went to the PDC a couple of weeks ago. But I heard it myself at the BPI &amp;amp; Workflow conference earlier this october. The new workflow designer that Workflow Foundation features will substitute the good ol’ orchestration designer in BizTalk vNext. This means that in the near future BizTalk Server and Workflow Foundation will grow to each other and will make a very strong team in delivering high available and reliable business solution.</description></item><item><title>BizUnit 2.0 released</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/10/bizunit-20-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2005 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/10/bizunit-20-released/</guid><description>A few weeks ago Kevin Smith (UK MCS Service Line Architect) released the second version of BizUnit. BizUnit is a framework for the automation of functional and regression testing of BizTalk solutions. Just think of NUnit ;).
The .MSI can be downloaded here: http://workspaces.gotdotnet.com/bizunit
It has a number of enhancements over the previous version that you can read about here: http://blogs.msdn.com/kevinsmi/archive/2005/07/17/439728.aspx.
BizUnit can be used in conjunction with Jason Births ‘Orchestration Profiler’ to ensure that a solution has an adequate level of test coverage allowing it to be deployed with confidence.</description></item><item><title>BizTalk 2006 Beta 1</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/10/biztalk-2006-beta-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2005 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/10/biztalk-2006-beta-1/</guid><description>I don’t believe any of you guys missed this, but about two months ago Microsoft released the first Beta of BizTalk Server 2006. Boy what a lot improvements are in the package. Here a short list of new or altered features:
Much easier installation (next, next, finish) Single mmc for all your administration needs Easy creation of deployment packages (MSI generation) Single-touch developer deployment In order message processing Subscribe to and handle suspended messages Browse button for file locations (yeah, it still wasn’t there!</description></item><item><title>Joining the overloaded web-log community</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/10/joining-the-overloaded-web-log-community/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2005 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/10/joining-the-overloaded-web-log-community/</guid><description>Today I joined the web-log community and will, as many others, post my personal opinions and findings on various subjects, but specificly BizTalk Server. I’m an Avanade consultant working in the Netherlands and specialized in business process integration using BizTalk Server. This means a lot of information on this blog will be about BizTalk. Aside from that I’ll also keep you updated on some of my hobby’s like Windows Media Center, XBOX360 and whatever else comes to mind.</description></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/search/</guid><description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml ``` [outputs] home = [&amp;ldquo;HTML&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;JSON&amp;rdquo;] ```</description></item></channel></rss>