<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sander Schutten's Blog</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/</link><description>Recent content on Sander Schutten's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 13:20:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Day 0: arrived in LA</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/day-0-arrived-in-la/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 13:20:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/day-0-arrived-in-la/</guid><description>Yesterday afternoon we (my collegues and I) arrived in LA. Purpose of visit: the Microsoft Professional Developer Conference 2008 (PDC’08). It promises to be a very interesting week with a lot of new stuff from Microsoft, including Windows 7, ‘Oslo’ and ‘Dublin’. After arrival we checked into our rooms, grabbed a slice of pizza, had a drink and went to bed. We tried to join the party by Jeffrey Pallermo, but the waiting time was about 40 minutes and we heard there was no more beer (no problem for me as non-alcohol drinking person, but some of my collegues seemed to mind :)).</description></item><item><title>Consume WCF service using Sharepoint Designer</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/consume-wcf-service-using-sharepoint-designer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 08:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/consume-wcf-service-using-sharepoint-designer/</guid><description>By default the SharePoint Designer is unable to consume WCF services because it fails to recognize the structure of the request messages. There is a workaround if you still need to consume WCF services using the Designer. However, this does not work via the datasource wizard but instead requires some manual intervention. There are two methods to do accomplish this:
Modify the datasource Modify the code in the page The first method is easier to implement and gives you more control over the output.</description></item><item><title>Better WSSF solution structure</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/better-wssf-solution-structure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 07:53:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2008/10/better-wssf-solution-structure/</guid><description>I’ve done my share of work with the Web Service Software Factory modelling edition, but never have I liked the solution structure it generates for me. Or either the namespaces of the projects are wrong, or the paths became too long because of the fully qualified names I’d use. This time I reserved some time to tackle this once and for all. The result is an easy to apply patch for WSSF: Modelling Edition.</description></item></channel></rss>