<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sander Schutten's Blog</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/</link><description>Recent content on Sander Schutten's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2006 11:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DevDays 7 &amp;amp; 8 March</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/devdays-7-8-march/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2006 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/devdays-7-8-march/</guid><description>This March the DevDays are coming to Amsterdam and I will be there to speak on BizTalk Server 2006 together with collegae Matt Joe, who is flown in from Seattle. I will be doing some demos involving BAM and in-order processing.
Matt will also be accompanying Dennis Mulder in a very promising talk on Windows Workflow Foundation.
Last but not least my manager Edwin Jongsma will enlighten everyone on the subject of Software Factories (Domain Specific Languages).</description></item><item><title>BizTalk Load Generation Utility reloaded</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/biztalk-load-generation-utility-reloaded/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/biztalk-load-generation-utility-reloaded/</guid><description>The BizTalk load generation utility, originally released by Microsoft several months ago, was quickly removed from their downloads page for enhancement. The enhanced version is now available for download here.
The interesting part is that this tool works with the Performance Tester Tool of Larry Beck (see post below).</description></item><item><title>BizTalk Performance Tester released</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/biztalk-performance-tester-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 07:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2006/02/biztalk-performance-tester-released/</guid><description>Better late then never, but about a month ago Larry Beck released the completed version of the BizTalk Performance Tester (BTSPerfTester). This application is intended to provide developers with an easily implemented and predictable method of determining the maximum sustainable throughput of their BizTalk solutions.
You can get it from his blog here.</description></item></channel></rss>