<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Media Center on Sander Schutten&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://sschutten.github.io/tags/media-center/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Media Center on Sander Schutten&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2008 15:05:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sschutten.github.io/tags/media-center/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Vista Media Center Add-ins (Dutch)</title>
      <link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/building-vista-media-center-add-ins-dutch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2008 15:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/building-vista-media-center-add-ins-dutch/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a while since I wrote an article on developing Vista Media Center Add-ins. A month ago the article was published in the Dutch .Net Magazine and today I found the digital version is available as well. In the article I demonstrate how to use the Viddler.com API to get a list of videos and display them in your add-in. The goal was to build a player for Viddler.com videos, but unfortunately the API method for getting the raw video is still not available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control Windows Media Center with New Windows SideShow BETA Gadgets</title>
      <link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/control-windows-media-center-with-new-windows-sideshow-beta-gadgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2008 10:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/control-windows-media-center-with-new-windows-sideshow-beta-gadgets/</guid>
      <description>From the Windows Experience Blog:
 The Windows SideShow Team has announced the availability of 4 BETA Windows SideShow Gadgets that let you control Windows Media Center from a Windows Sideshow device. You can sign-up via Microsoft Connect to gain access to Beta Test these new Windows SideShow Gadgets:
http://connect.microsoft.com/InvitationUse.aspx?ProgramID=2380&amp;amp;SiteID=312&amp;amp;InvitationID=GPB-79MM-RFJ2
Here is the breakdown of the 4 Windows Media Center BETA Windows SideShow Gadgets and what they do:
 Now Playing: View what is currently playing in Windows Media Center (includes playback controls) Pictures + Video: Browse your Photos and Videos folders Music: Browse your Music folder and play any song TV: Look at what is on TV via the Windows Media Center Guide, Schedule Recordings, and View Recordings (in a Thumbnail view)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status update on MCE Guide Editor</title>
      <link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/status-update-on-mce-guide-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 17:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/status-update-on-mce-guide-editor/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people are waiting for a new release of MCE Guide Editor which hopefully fixes the bug that the channel order gets mixed up again after a reboot. Somewhere in the comments of the old post I mentioned I thought I’d found the bug and it was just a matter of days until the fix could be released. I was testing the tool agains a simulated set-up with preconfigured UPC guide listings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>