<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sander Schutten's Blog</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/</link><description>Recent content on Sander Schutten's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 13:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BizTalk Server 2006 CTM Released</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/biztalk-server-2006-ctm-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/biztalk-server-2006-ctm-released/</guid><description>As per monday October 7th Microsoft released BizTalk Server 2006 CTM. This release is only available for users with a MSDN or TechNet account. The CTM release of BizTalk Server 2006 is fully compatible with Visual Studio 2005 and SQL Server 2005. I just can smell the RTM version coming very soon.</description></item><item><title>Access message properties inside custom pipeline component</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/access-message-properties-inside-custom-pipeline-component/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 09:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/access-message-properties-inside-custom-pipeline-component/</guid><description>Just recently I was looking for some default message properties and how to read and write them inside a custom pipeline component. While searching I stumbled over a great post listing all the default message properties and how to read them.
If you want to access the properties in your custom pipeline component, you have to get the IBaseMessageContext object from the IBaseContext and use the Read method to get a value or the Write method to substitute a value with your own.</description></item><item><title>BizTalk&amp;#039;s sexy new XSLT mapper</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/biztalks-sexy-new-xslt-mapper/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 08:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2005/11/biztalks-sexy-new-xslt-mapper/</guid><description>I’ve just watched a clip from Channel9 featuring Eddie Churchill. In the video he demonstrates a prototype of the future BizTalk mapper. The new mapper will contain some very impressive features as I must say. Some of them make the life of the mapper a lot easier, especially when dealing with large maps.
Some of the features which are shown in the video are:
Different drawing densities for lines which are in view and which aren’t.</description></item></channel></rss>