<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sander Schutten's Blog</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/</link><description>Recent content on Sander Schutten's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 11:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MIX11: Day 3</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-day-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 11:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-day-3/</guid><description>It’s a wrap, MIX11 is over. Yesterday was the last day of MIX and many people have already returned to their homes. There was not much news to be shared, but here are my findings anyway.
Designer and Developer: A Case for the Hybrid (Jeff Croft) In this talk Jeff Croft talks about what makes good designers and developers. His statement is that designers should know how to program and developers should know how to design.</description></item><item><title>MIX11: Day 2</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-day-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 11:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-day-2/</guid><description>Today was a really interesting day, with lots of new stuff being announced and sessions packed with interesting information. These are my findings of this day.
Keynote (Joe Belfiore, Scott Guthrie) The keynote started off with an inspiring viral video. It appears a fan of Windows Phone created it by request of Microsoft after he created his own viral out of love of the phone. If the viral gets over 200k of views on YouTube, it is turned into a real commercial.</description></item><item><title>MIX11: Day 1</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-day-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 11:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-day-1/</guid><description>Today was the first conference day and my second day at MIX11. The day began with a keynote and after that a couple of sessions. These are my findings of today.
Keynote (Dean Hachamovitch, Scott Guthrie) Dean started off with looking back at the development of IE9 and how successful is has been so far. Then he announced that they’re already three weeks into development of IE10, which didn’t come as a surprise looking at the shirt he was wearing with a bit TEN on it with the ‘E’ being the IE logo.</description></item><item><title>MIX11: Boot Camps</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-boot-camps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 11:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/04/mix11-boot-camps/</guid><description>Today was the preconference day at MIX11, which means boot camps for everyone that applied for them. There were options for the morning and afternoon boot camps and I chose the Silverlight and SharePoint &amp;amp; Silverlight boot camps. This is a brief summary of what I think were things of interest.
Silverlight boot camp I didn’t came to this boot camp to improve my knowledge on Silverlight, but more because of the speakers: John Papa and Mike Taulty.</description></item></channel></rss>