<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WCF on Sander Schutten's Blog</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/categories/wcf/</link><description>Recent content in WCF on Sander Schutten's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 08:29:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sschutten.github.io/categories/wcf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Consume WCF service using Sharepoint Designer</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/consume-wcf-service-using-sharepoint-designer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 08:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/consume-wcf-service-using-sharepoint-designer/</guid><description>By default the SharePoint Designer is unable to consume WCF services because it fails to recognize the structure of the request messages. There is a workaround if you still need to consume WCF services using the Designer. However, this does not work via the datasource wizard but instead requires some manual intervention. There are two methods to do accomplish this:
Modify the datasource Modify the code in the page The first method is easier to implement and gives you more control over the output.</description></item><item><title>Video: BizTalk Services Explained</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/video-biztalk-services-explained/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2008 11:32:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/video-biztalk-services-explained/</guid><description>In this video, James Conard talks with John Shewchuk and Dennis Pilarinos about BizTalk Services.
In the simplest definition, BizTalk Services simplifies application connectivity by extending WCF and providing a set of hosted services. John and Dennis quickly explain BizTalk Services by discussing the challenges with building applications today. Dennis also shows four demos of BizTalk Services and then drops into Visual Studio along the way to show the programming model.</description></item><item><title>First look at WCF Adapter for BizTalk Server 2006 R2</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/first-look-at-wcf-adapter-for-biztalk-server-2006-r2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 13:17:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/first-look-at-wcf-adapter-for-biztalk-server-2006-r2/</guid><description>Although the WCF adapter for BizTalk Server 2006 R2 has been released a while ago, I found that a coworker of mine had created a simple and short video explaining all the basics of using the WCF adapter. If you haven’t used the adapter before or just want to see how easy it is to use the adapter, go see the video here.</description></item></channel></rss>