<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Silverlight on Sander Schutten's Blog</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/categories/silverlight/</link><description>Recent content in Silverlight on Sander Schutten's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 18:10:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sschutten.github.io/categories/silverlight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lightswitch: custom ribbon button</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/08/lightswitch-custom-ribbon-button/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 18:10:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/08/lightswitch-custom-ribbon-button/</guid><description>Two weeks ago, on July 26th, Visual Studio Lightswitch 2011 was released. I ‘d seen a couple of videos what you can do with Lightswitch so I though I’d put it to the test by developing a replacement for a tool I use at one of my clients. Lightswitch is really easy to use and I believe I can actually teach my wife to create data-centric application using it. Until you reach the limits though, because than it becomes more difficult really fast.</description></item><item><title>Using the Sync Framework on Windows Phone 7</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/01/using-the-sync-framework-on-windows-phone-7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 13:18:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2011/01/using-the-sync-framework-on-windows-phone-7/</guid><description>For a mobile platform, like Windows Phone 7, you may be required to allow an application to work even when there’s no data connection available. Doing so is not that easy. You need to manage state locally, synchronize changed data (one-way or duplex) and maybe even handle conflicts. Luckily Microsoft offers the Sync Framework which makes it easier for you to accomplish this by taking much of the required plumbing out of your hands completely.</description></item><item><title>WCF RIA Services OData endpoint does NOT support update or LINQ</title><link>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2010/11/wcf-ria-services-odata-endpoint-does-not-support-update-or-linq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 17:46:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sschutten.github.io/posts/2010/11/wcf-ria-services-odata-endpoint-does-not-support-update-or-linq/</guid><description>After struggling with WCF RIA Services v1 (Silverlight 4 RTM) to enable insert/update for the OData endpoint for use with Windows Phone 7, I finally figured it out. The current version of WCF RIA Services does NOT support update or LINQ! I think I searched for a couple of hours until I found the single line of information on this in this following Silverlight TV post:
NOTE: The ODATA endpoint has very limited support in V1.</description></item></channel></rss>